Hello everyone and welcome back to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Kathryn and today we have an elementary level lesson about food, one of my favorite
我是Kathryn，今天我们有一个关于食物的初级课程，这是我最喜欢的话题之一。
things to talk about.
谈论的事情。
That's right.
没错。
We are going to talk about food but specifically we're going to talk about a family barbecue.
我们要谈论食物，但具体来说，我们要谈论家庭烧烤。
Okay, what is a family barbecue?
好的，什么是家庭烧烤？
Well, I'll just say a few words first.
嗯，我先简单说几句。
A barbecue is usually something that we do outside.
烧烤通常是我们户外进行的事情。
We bring food, we play games, maybe have some drinks and a lot of the food is grilled.
我们带食物，玩游戏，可能喝点饮料，很多食物都是烤制的。
So that's what we're talking about today.
这就是我们今天要讨论的内容。
We're going to hear this dialogue first and then we'll come back to talk about it.
我们先听这段对话，然后回来讨论。
Is everything ready for the big family barbecue tomorrow?
明天大型家庭烧烤的一切都准备好了吗？
Yep, the steaks and chicken are marinated and I also bought hamburger buns.
是的，牛排和鸡肉已经腌制好了，我还买了汉堡面包。
We should also cook a couple dozen hot dogs and kebabs.
我们还应该烤几打热狗和烤肉串。
Yeah, good idea.
嗯，好主意。
We could put some lawn furniture outside next to the grill.
我们可以在烤架旁边放一些草坪家具。
I also set up the tent outside so we can hide from the sun if it gets too hot.
我还在外面搭了帐篷，这样如果太热了，我们可以躲太阳。
Great!
太好了！
I asked Grace to bring cups and serviettes as she is also bringing two big coolers for
我让Grace带杯子和餐巾，因为她还要带两个大冷藏箱来装啤酒。
the beers.
装啤酒。
This is going to be a great barbecue.
这将是一次很棒的烧烤。
Oh no, it's raining.
哦不，下雨了。
Alright, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So probably a couple of words you didn't really understand.
所以可能有一些词你们不太理解。
So let's take a look at those now in Language Takeaway.
现在让我们在“语言要点”部分看看这些词。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
Lots of food words, Marco.
很多食物词汇，Marco。
The first one is barbecue.
第一个是“barbecue”。
We were talking about that a minute ago.
我们刚才一直在谈论这个。
A barbecue is something we do usually for a special occasion or for dinner.
烧烤通常是我们为特殊场合或晚餐做的事情。
It's a summertime thing.
这是夏天的事情。
You go outside when it's warm and the entire family comes and we have food.
天气暖和时你出去，全家人都来，我们吃食物。
Sometimes people even bring food.
有时人们甚至自带食物。
Right.
对。
So usually as you mentioned, it's something that you do a barbecue.
所以通常像你提到的，这是你做的事情——烧烤。
You have a family barbecue.
你有一个家庭烧烤。
But it's also a verb.
但它也是一个动词。
To barbecue something.
烧烤某物。
So to cook meat on a barbecue.
意思是在烤架上烹饪肉。
So that's cooking meat not in a stove, not with gas.
所以那不是用炉子或煤气烹饪肉。
Usually it's under a fire or very warm intense heat coming from coals.
通常是在火上或来自煤炭的非常高温下。
Exactly.
没错。
And so before we cook food, usually before we cook meat on the grill, before we barbecue
所以在烹饪食物之前，通常在我们烤架上烹饪肉之前，在我们烧烤它之前，
it, we have to marinate it.
我们必须腌制它。
So in this situation, the steaks and the chicken are already marinated.
所以在这种情况下，牛排和鸡肉已经腌制好了。
Okay.
好的。
So to marinate something or which is a verb or the steaks and chickens are marinated which
所以“to marinate something”是动词，或者“the steaks and chickens are marinated”是形容词形式。
is an adjective.
是形容词。
So basically means that you have added spices and maybe some lemon juice, different herbs
所以基本上意味着你在肉上加了香料、可能一些柠檬汁、不同的香草或盐，以便在烹饪前给肉增添风味。
or salts to the meats in order to give it flavor before you cook them.
或者盐，以便在烹饪前给肉增添风味。
Exactly.
没错。
So in Indian cooking for example, you marinate with a yogurt sauce and you leave the meat
比如在印度烹饪中，你用酸奶酱腌制，然后把肉放在冰箱里一整夜。
in the refrigerator for a whole night.
放在冰箱里一整夜。
So marinating or to marinate is a process to give flavor to food.
所以腌制是一个给食物增添风味的过程。
Very good.
很好。
Alright.
好的。
So we've marinated our food, our chicken, our steaks.
所以我们腌制了食物，我们的鸡肉、牛排。
But also we have hamburgers.
但我们还有汉堡。
So we need hamburger buns.
所以我们需要汉堡面包。
What are buns?
什么是面包？
Okay.
好的。
Buns are pieces of bread that are for special kinds of food.
面包是用于特殊食物的面包片。
So you have a hamburger bun.
所以你有汉堡面包。
It's a round piece of bread and the hamburger goes on one piece and under another piece.
它是一个圆形的面包片，汉堡放在一片上面，另一片下面。
A hot dog bun is different.
热狗面包不同。
It's like a piece of bread that's folded and the hot dog goes in the middle.
它像一片折叠的面包，热狗放在中间。
So bun is a special kind of bread for these kinds of foods.
所以面包是用于这类食物的特殊面包。
Alright.
好的。
So remember, if you want to have a hot dog, you need to buy hot dog buns.
所以记住，如果你想有热狗，你需要买热狗面包。
So people know already that you're talking about bread.
这样人们就知道你在说面包。
And if you want to buy a hamburger bread, you say a hamburger bun.
如果你想买汉堡面包，你说“a hamburger bun”。
That's right.
没错。
So hamburger buns and hot dog buns.
所以汉堡面包和热狗面包。
But after we talk about having the hamburger buns, we discuss how many hot dogs we're going
但在我们讨论完汉堡面包后，我们讨论要烤多少热狗。
to cook.
要烤多少热狗。
So the person says, we should cook a couple dozen hot dogs.
所以那个人说：“我们应该烤几打热狗。”
Alright.
好的。
So a dozen is 12 units of something.
所以“a dozen”是12个单位的东西。
Right.
对。
So eggs are sold in dozens.
鸡蛋是按打卖的。
We buy a dozen eggs.
我们买一打鸡蛋。
We buy 12 eggs.
我们买12个鸡蛋。
Okay.
好的。
Or you can say half a dozen.
或者你可以说半打。
That means 6.
那就是6个。
Half of 12.
12的一半。
But a couple dozen is usually around 24, 25.
但“几打”通常指24到25个左右。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
很好。
So a dozen hot dogs and they are also getting kebabs.
所以一打热狗，他们还要买烤肉串。
What are kebabs?
什么是烤肉串？
One of my favorite foods, kebabs are sticks or skewers of meat.
我最喜欢的食物之一，烤肉串就是把肉串在签子或扦子上。
So you have a very thin stick and you put the meat on it and you put that on the grill
你有一根很细的签子，把肉穿上去，然后放在烤架上
and you cook the meat on the grill.
在烤架上烤肉。
So yeah, those are very common.
是的，这些很常见。
For example, in the Middle East, right?
比如，在中东地区，对吧？
You have kebabs, sticks of meat and also maybe some vegetables put on it and you grill them.
有烤肉串，肉串上可能还放些蔬菜，然后一起烤。
Exactly.
没错。
Very flavorful, very tasty meat.
味道浓郁、非常美味的肉。
Alright.
好的。
So why don't we listen to our dialogue again and we'll come back shortly to look at some
那我们再听一遍对话，稍后回来学习更多
more words.
词汇。
Is everything ready for the big family barbecue tomorrow?
明天的大型家庭烧烤聚会，一切都准备好了吗？
Yep.
是的。
The steaks and chicken are marinated and I also bought hamburger buns.
牛排和鸡肉都腌好了，我还买了汉堡面包。
We should also cook a couple dozen hot dogs and kebabs.
我们还应该烤几打热狗和烤肉串。
Yeah, good idea.
好主意。
We could put some lawn furniture outside next to the grill.
我们可以在外面的烤架旁边放些草坪家具。
I also set up the tent outside so we can hide from the sun if it gets too hot.
我还在外面搭了帐篷，这样如果太热了我们可以躲太阳。
Great.
太好了。
I asked Grace to bring cups and serviettes as she is also bringing two big coolers for
我让格蕾丝带杯子和餐巾纸，因为她还要带两个大冷藏箱
the beers.
来装啤酒。
This is going to be a great barbecue.
这将会是一次很棒的烧烤。
Alright we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now why don't we go to a second part of language takeaway and take a look at five
现在让我们进入“语言要点”的第二部分，看看另外五个
more words.
词汇。
Language takeaway.
语言要点。
Alright the first word that we're going to look at is lawn furniture.
好的，我们要看的第一个词是“草坪家具”。
So we're going to have lawn furniture outside.
所以我们要在外面放草坪家具。
Okay so before we even start thinking about food, we have to decide where people will
好的，在我们开始考虑食物之前，必须先决定大家在烧烤时
sit at this barbecue.
坐在哪里。
And so we have to find out how much lawn furniture we have.
所以我们要看看有多少草坪家具。
Furniture can be a sofa, a table, a chair.
家具可以是沙发、桌子、椅子。
We have furniture in the house.
我们家里有家具。
But lawn furniture is furniture for the outside.
但草坪家具是户外用的家具。
A lawn is the green grass outside your house.
草坪就是你房子外面的绿色草地。
So it's usually not going to be made out of wood for example because if it rains it might
所以通常不会用木头做，因为如果下雨，它可能会
get ruined right.
被损坏，对吧。
So usually it's either plastic or maybe even rock or stone.
所以通常是用塑料，甚至可能是岩石或石头做的。
Or metal.
或者金属。
So that's what lawn furniture is.
这就是草坪家具。
Furniture that is made to be outside in your backyard for example or that sits on your
就是专门放在外面，比如后院，或者放在
lawn.
草坪上的家具。
Exactly.
没错。
And so we're going to be on the lawn furniture.
所以我们要坐在草坪家具上。
We have the special thing for cooking meat outside, the grill.
我们有专门在户外烤肉的东西，就是烤架。
Okay so we mentioned that you grill chicken or you grill steaks.
好的，我们提到过烤鸡肉或烤牛排。
But it's also a noun.
但它也是名词。
A grill.
烤架。
So a grill, what is that?
那么烤架是什么？
A grill is like a stove for the outside but instead of having electricity to make the
烤架就像户外的炉子，但不用电生火，
fire we have gas or propane.
而是用煤气或丙烷。
And this is something that we light on fire and we use coals to keep the insides very
我们点燃它，用木炭保持内部
warm.
很热。
And so this is just a way to cook meats or even vegetables outside.
这就是一种在户外烹饪肉类甚至蔬菜的方式。
Okay perfect.
好的，完美。
So that is a grill.
那就是烤架。
And if you're going to cook foods or vegetables in this way, so you're going to grill them.
如果你要用这种方式烹饪食物或蔬菜，那就是烤它们。
Alright.
好的。
And well just in case it gets hot and you want to hide from the sun, we are going to
而且，万一天气热了你想躲太阳，我们还要
set up a tent.
搭一个帐篷。
Okay a tent, you can sleep in a tent but in this case a tent is just a covering outside.
好的，帐篷，你可以在里面睡觉，但这里帐篷只是户外的遮蔽物。
So maybe some cloth or some fabric that will stand over us when we sit down or want to
可能是一些布料或织物，当我们坐下或想在户外时，
be outside.
它会在我们上方撑起来。
It's also a way to protect us from the rain.
它也能保护我们免受雨淋。
Alright so as you mentioned a tent is something that you set up temporarily made out of cloth
好的，就像你提到的，帐篷是用布料或塑料临时搭建的东西，
or plastic to protect you from the sun or rain.
用来防晒或防雨。
Or if you're going camping you sleep in one.
或者如果你去露营，你会在里面睡觉。
Alright and now that they have all the food, they need cups and then they mentioned this
好了，现在他们有了所有食物，还需要杯子，然后他们提到了这个
strange word, it kind of sounds French, serviettes.
奇怪的词，听起来有点像法语，serviettes（餐巾）。
So I do think it comes from the French word.
所以我确实认为它来自法语词。
This is a British way of saying napkins.
这是英式英语中表示 napkins（餐巾）的说法。
So it's like paper for cleaning your hands and cleaning your mouth that you throw away.
所以就是用来擦手和擦嘴的纸，用完就扔掉。
Okay so you can say napkins or if you want to sound a little bit more fancier you can
好的，所以你可以说 napkins，或者如果你想听起来更讲究一点，你可以
say serviettes.
说 serviettes。
And speaking of fancy, let's talk about beer.
说到讲究，我们来聊聊啤酒。
Where do we keep beer?
我们把啤酒放在哪里？
It has to stay cold right?
它得保持冰凉，对吧？
Right so usually you would place it in a refrigerator but if you're outside or you're going camping,
对，所以通常你会把它放在冰箱里，但如果你在外面或者去露营，
you want to keep them cold or you want to keep something hot.
你想让它们保持冰凉，或者你想让某样东西保持热乎。
You place it in a cooler.
你就把它放在一个 cooler（保温箱）里。
Okay so a cooler is a plastic bin or a plastic box that we put all of the ice in and the
好的，所以 cooler 是一个塑料箱或塑料盒，我们把所有冰块和
drinks so it's not just for beer, it's also for coke and Sprite and all these different
饮料放进去，它不只是用来放啤酒，也用来放可乐、雪碧和各种
drinks.
饮料。
Right so it's usually made to keep something cool but as I said if you want to keep something
对，所以它通常用来保持东西凉爽，但就像我说的，如果你想保持东西
warm you can also keep it in the cooler.
温热，你也可以把它放在保温箱里。
It keeps the temperature of the foods.
它能保持食物的温度。
And the nice thing is that it's not electric so you can use it anywhere.
而且好处是它不用电，所以你在任何地方都能用。
Right.
对。
Alright so that's all the words for today.
好了，这就是今天的所有单词。
Why don't we listen to our dialogue for the last time.
我们最后再听一遍对话吧。
Is everything ready for the big family barbecue tomorrow?
明天的大型家庭烧烤聚会，一切都准备好了吗？
Yep, the steaks and chicken are marinated and I also bought hamburger buns.
是的，牛排和鸡肉都腌好了，我还买了汉堡面包。
We should also cook a couple dozen hot dogs and kebabs.
我们还应该烤几十个热狗和烤肉串。
Yeah, good idea.
嗯，好主意。
We could put some lawn furniture outside next to the grill.
我们可以在外面烤架旁边放一些草坪家具。
I also set up the tent outside so we can hide from the sun if it gets too hot.
我还在外面搭了帐篷，这样如果太热了，我们可以躲太阳。
Great!
太好了！
We asked Grace to bring cups and serviettes as she is also bringing two big coolers for
我们让 Grace 带杯子和餐巾，因为她还会带两个大保温箱来
the beers.
装啤酒。
This is going to be a great barbecue.
这将会是一次很棒的烧烤。
Oh no, it's raining.
哦不，下雨了。
Alright we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So family barbecues and doing these things.
所以家庭烧烤和做这些事情。
Did you do these when you were young at home?
你小时候在家做过这些吗？
Do you still like to do it?
你现在还喜欢做吗？
All the time.
经常做。
I love barbecues.
我喜欢烧烤。
It's one of my favorite ways to eat food.
这是我最喜欢的吃东西方式之一。
The nice thing about a barbecue is you get to sit outside and relax and there's nothing
烧烤的好处是你可以坐在外面放松，没有什么比
better than nice fresh grilled meat.
新鲜烤好的肉更好的了。
Right, and well you have all your friends over so you're having a couple of beers and
对，而且你邀请所有朋友过来，喝几杯啤酒，
you're having some meat and it's actually a really nice way of just having something
吃点肉，这其实是一种很好的方式，在家里
at home with good friends and family, right?
和好朋友及家人一起享受，对吧？
Exactly, and some of the most important barbecues we have are in the summer near July 4th.
没错，而且我们一些最重要的烧烤是在夏天，临近七月四日的时候。
And so people like to have July 4th barbecues where you celebrate Independence Day and sit
所以人们喜欢举办七月四日烧烤，庆祝独立日，坐在
outside and drink and have hot dogs and hamburgers and macaroni and cheese.
外面喝酒，吃热狗、汉堡包和通心粉奶酪。
Actually while I was in Chile I noticed that as well near their festivities for their independence
实际上，我在智利的时候也注意到，在他们庆祝独立日的节日期间，
which is September 18th.
也就是九月十八日。
A lot of people get together and have barbecues and it's so so popular that pretty much every
很多人聚在一起烧烤，这非常非常流行，几乎每个
house in the neighborhood you can smell somebody barbecuing on the weekend.
街区的房子在周末都能闻到有人在烧烤的味道。
You're making me so hungry.
你让我好饿啊。
Alright guys so if you have any questions, any doubts or if it's common for you guys
好了，各位，如果你们有任何问题、任何疑问，或者如果烧烤在你们家乡
to barbecue back home then why don't you send us a couple of comments at EnglishPod.com
很常见，那么为什么不给我们发几条评论到 EnglishPod.com 呢，
and we'll see everyone there.
我们会在那里见大家。
Bye!
再见！